Carlos Quintero González

Systems Engineer - Front End Junior Developer

I am a Front End Junior Developer. I'm 23, I've dedicated my professional career as WEB and IOS developer. I have been able to nurture my knowledge in these skills thanks to my work experience, and my constant personal study. Likewise, I am self-taught, dedicating myself to improve my skills through practice and taking courses.

Education

Bachelor's degree in Computer Systems Engineering at Jean Piaget University (Veracruz, Mexico)

August 2019 - July 2022

Recently finished studying Master's Degree in IT and Cybersecurity at Jean Piaget University (Veracruz, Mexico)

October 2022 - Present

Languages

Spanish and English (Level B1 - Cambridge Key English Test [KET], Pass with Distinction: Overall score: 142)

Work Experience

Systems Engineer at Panadería La Especial S.A. de C.V. ('The Especial' Bakery) [Veracruz, Mexico] November 2020 - November 2023

Technical support for all the branches, Database management, creation of applications for the company platform (assistance, orders, sales calculation, etc.). Code review, problem solving and development of new features in several WEB applications using HTML, JS, PHP, MySQL.

Software Development Engineer at UNINDETEC (Mexico Navy - Research and Technological Development Unit) [Veracruz, Mexico]

November 2023 - April 2024

Software Development Engineer in charge of improving projects for the IOS platform, participating in the development and deployment of a secure messaging IOS application. Code implementation in advanced projects compatible with Objective-C, Swift, UIKit and SwiftUI frameworks.

Online courses

Object Oriented Programming in Java by UC San Diego

at Coursera

October 2020

It was paramount in gaining my general understanding of the OOP Paradigm.

The Full Stack React Course by developedbyed (Creative Programming and Design Courses)

at Teachable

September 2022

I acquired advanced knowledge about user interaction, event triggers, screen changes and API queries. I understood how important is the User Experience on web apps. I became familiar with creating custom components by adding styles manually or complimenting them with pre-build components in design frameworks as well (e.g. ChakraUI, FramerMotion, StyledComponents).

Definitive Guide: Learn the 9 Advanced Patterns in ReactJS by Juan Developero at Udemv

March 2023

I learned about predefined developing patterns to apply them in particular cases, reusable code (avoiding redundancy and excessive file size), and also learned about how important modularity is in developing projects.

Skills

Soft Skills

- Quick adaptability
- Good attitude
- **Patience**
- **Effort**
- Teamwork
- decision making
- Positivism
- Team Communication
- Frustration management

Hard Skills

- JavaScript
- React
- Node.js
- Next.js
- PHP
- SQL
- **OOP Paradigm**
- Java
- **GIT**
- Python
- Swift
- SwiftUI
- UlKit
- Objective-C